Chandler P. Anderson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Speeches and Writings File, 1907-1936 (Box 58-60)
  - Articles, speeches, and editorials
    - 1921
      - “American-British Claims Arbitration Tribunal
      - “Peace with Germany
    - 1922, “The Power of Public Opinion for Peace”
    - 1923, “Plan by Which the United States May Cooperate with Other Nations to Achieve the Peace of the World”
    - 1924, “Exclusion Law and Diplomacy
    - 1925
      - “Claims against Germany”
      - “International Control and Distribution of Raw Materials”
    - 1926
      - “Title of Confiscated Property”
      - “Exploitation of the Products of the Sea”
    - 1927
      - “Inviolability of Private Property against Confiscation”
      - “Basis of the Law against Confiscating Foreign Owned Property”
      - “Projects for the Codification of American International Law”
    - 1928 (Box 59)
      - “New Arbitration Treaty with France”
      - “Arbitration of Attorneys' Fees under the Settlement of the War Claims Act of 1928
    - 1929, “Scope and Character of Arbitration Treaties”
    - 1930, “Immunity of Neutral Sea Borne Commerce”
    - 1931
      - “Final Liquidation of German War Reparations”
      - “Our Policy of Non-Recognition in Central America”
      - “Basis of an Advisory Opinion by the World Court on the Proposed Austro-German Customs Union”
      - “The St. Lawrence Waterway Project”
    - 1932
      - “The Senate and Obligatory Arbitration Treaties”
      - “Advisory Opinions from Commissions of Inquiry”
      - “ Harmonizing the League Covenant and the Peace Pact”
    - 1933, “ Production of Evidence by Subpoena before International Tribunals”
    - 1934, “Recognition of Russia
    - 1935
      - and “Assignment of Claims by the Russian Government to the United States”
      - “Treaties as Domestic Law”
      - “Recent Trade Agreements with Russia”
      - “Frustration of President Wilson's Attempt to Commit the Senate to Endorsement of League of Nations”
      - “The Price of Freedom of Seas” (Box 60)
    - 1936
      - “Revision of Paris Peace Treaty to Protect American Interests”
      - “Monroe Doctrine Distinguished in Principle from Mutual Protective Pacts”
    - Undated, “Immunity of a State from Suit in the Supreme Court by a Foreign Government without State's Consent”
  - Book reviews, 1924-1936
- Miscellany, 1896-1936 (Box 61-63)
  Biographical material, clippings, commissions passports, invitations, autographs, and printed matter.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Biographical file (Box 61)
  - Clippings
  - Commissions See Oversize
  - Printed matter
  - Printed matter (Box 62)
  - Printed matter (Box 63)
- Oversize (Box OV 1)
  Commissions.
  Described according to the container and series from which the items were removed.
  - Commissions (Container 61) (Box OV 1)